我忘了我当时是否哭了
I can't remember if I cried
在我听说他的新娘失去了新郎
When I read about his widowed bride
不知是什么让我内心触动
And something touched me deep inside
那天音乐…
The day the music...
紫外线辐射水平较高
UV radiation high.
温度摄氏66度 请小心
Temperature, 150 degrees. Caution.
体温较高 摄氏38.4度
Body temperature high, 101.2.
好的…
Okay. Okay.
杜威
Dewey.
再见了 美国派小姐
SoBye, bye, bye Miss American Pie
开着我的雪佛兰来到堤坝畔
Drove my Chevy to the levee
但是堤坝已经干涸
But the levee was dry
兄弟们在喝黑麦威士忌
And them good ole boysWere drinking whiskey and rye
唱道这将是我死去的那天
Singin' this'll be the day that I die
这将是我死去的那天
This'll be the day that I die
杜威 瓶子
Dewey, bottle.
是你写了关于爱的书吗？你又是否会笃信上帝
Did you write the book of loveAnd do you have faith in God above
若《圣经》让你这么做？ 若《圣经》让你这么做？
If the Bible tells you so? If the Bible tells you so?
嘿 你相信摇滚吗？
Hey, do you believe in rock and roll?
音乐…
Can music--
能拯救凡人的灵魂吗？
Save your mortal soul?
你能教我怎么跳舞吗？
And can you teach me to dance...
宠物护理 宠物配件
好的
Okay.
今晚有只小家伙要开心了
Someone's going to be happy tonight.
K9最优狗粮 牛肉和肝
天啊
Jesus.
又来
Getting old.
那时我是血气方刚的孤独少年
I was a lonely teenage bronckin' buck
带着一枝粉色康乃馨 开着一辆皮卡车
With a pink carnationAnd a pickup truck
但我并不走运 音乐死去的那一天
Knew I was out of luckThe day the music died
来吧 收起前板
All right. Front's up.
已清查
完成
Done.
好的
Okay.
我唱道
So I was singing
抱歉
Sorry.
已清查
而国王…
While the king...
警告 气压下降
Warning. Air pressure drop.
请小心
Caution.
警告 气压下降
Warning. Air pressure drop.
请小心
Caution.
不好 该死
No. Oh, shit.
460米
1,500 feet.
430米
1,400 feet.
400米
1,300 feet.
360米
1,200 feet.
-270米  -来吧
-900 feet.  -Come on.
240米
800 feet.
210米
700 feet.
天啊 来吧
Oh, my God. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
180米
600 feet.
120米
400 feet.
TAE技术公司
90米
300 feet.
60米
200 feet.
警告 请寻找掩蔽地点
Warning. Shelter advised.
我来了
I'm coming.
30米
100 feet.
来吧
Come on.
-24米  -来吧
-80 feet.  -Come on.
18米
60 feet.
-12米  -好
-40 feet.  -Here we go.
好的
Okay.
进来吧 我拉着你
Let's go. I got ya.
来吧
Come on!
进来
In!
好 轮到你了
Okay. Your turn.
眼睛也要清洗干净
Get the eyeballs.
爪子抬起来
Up with the paw.
向上看
Eyes up.
向上 来吧
Up. Come on.
TAE技术公司 芬奇温伯格
好的 楼下见
All right. See you downstairs.
温馨的家
嘿 我可没忘了你 嘿 我可没忘了你
Hey. I didn't forget about you. Hey. I didn't forget about you.
什么？你想我了？对 我也很想你
What? Did you miss me? Yes, I missed you.
对 我一直都在想你 真的
Yes, I think about you all the time.Yes, I do. Yeah.
对…
Yeah. Yeah.
来 挠挠肚子 我就是做这个的 对吧？
Yes, I'll give you scratches.That's all I'm here for, right?
只为了给你挠肚子
Just to scratch you.
狗
今晚就不能安安静静地度过吗？
Now can we please havea quiet evening at home tonight?
嘿 别闹了
Hey, cut it out.
真乖 杜威
Good boy, Dewey.
好的…别担心我 开吃吧
Okay, okay. Don't worry about me.Carry on.
桃子
世界之书 世界之书
人们一天到晚都在做什么？
哈勃的宇宙
犬类美容大全
给我的小王子 爱你的妈妈
小王子
谢谢 杜威
Thanks, Dewey.
弗利特伍德制造 南风旅行车
图像处理中
犬类美容大全
犬类护理训练
你好
Oh, hi.
你的球呢？在这里吗？你的球呢？
Where's your ball? Is it here?Is it here? Where's your ball?
去吧 捡回来
Go! Oh! Get it!
好的 轮到你了
All right, you're next.
来吧 小臭狗 过来
Come here, dog breath. Come on.
暴露在电离辐射中的影响
伽马射线耀斑和概率性灭绝事件 伽马射线耀斑和概率性灭绝事件
太阳能够以何种方式杀死我们
紫外线指数
伽马射线暴
伽马射线耀斑
《世界末日生存指南》 2028年5月
好的
Okay.
我需要用一下你的眼睛
Now I'm gonna need your eyes.
对不起 杜威
I'm sorry, Dewey.
我会给你换新的 我保证
I'll get you new ones. I promise.
一定会值得的
And it'll be worth it.
一个人的一小步
One small step for man...
是芬奇温伯格的巨大一步
one giant leap for Finch Weinberg.
指令：运行calibrate64.exe正在读取…
完成循环参数
数据传输
你好
Hello.
如果你能说话 请说“是”
If you can speak, say "yes."
机器人
“设备无响应或与运行系统不兼容
"This device is not responding or notcompatible with the operating system.
请致电技术支援部寻求协助”
Please call technical supportfor assistance."
好的
Okay.
嗨
Hey.
那点点头呢？
How about nodding your head?
如果你听得懂我说的话 就点点头
If you can understand me, nod your head.
不 我不知道为什么它无法运行
No, I don't know why he's not working.
你懂吗？你明白吗？
You do-- You do understand?Do you understand?
只有明白我问的问题时才点头
Only nod if I ask you a questionthat you understand.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
别再点头了
Stop nodding.
你明白
You understand.
别再点头了
Stop nodding your head.
你有新的朋友了 乖
You have a friend! Good boy.
是
Yeah.
好的 我做了点调整
Okay, I've done some tweaking.
和我设想的不太一样
Not exactly what I had in mind.
但对于现在来说够了
It should do for now.
如果你能说话 请说点什么
Now, if you can speak, say something.
别激动
Calm down.
点什么
Something.
点什么…没错
Something. Something, indeed.
没错
Indeed.
那么
So...
和我说点有趣的事吧
Tell me something interesting.
长颈鹿在没有水的情况下能比骆驼存活更久
Giraffes can survive without waterlonger than camels.
是真的吗？
Is that a fact?
我打赌你一定不知道
I bet you didn't know that.
更格卢鼠能比长颈鹿存活更久
Kangaroo rats can survivelonger than giraffes.
-好的…  -你知道吗…
-Okay. Okay, okay.  -Did you know--
和我说说关于你的趣事吧
Tell me something interesting about you.
我有四条主要指令
I have four primary directives.
第一条指令是什么？
What is the first directive?
第一条指令：机器人不能伤害人类
First directive:A robot cannot harm a human
也不能坐视人类受到伤害
or, through inaction,allow a human to be harmed.
嘿 别激动
Hey, calm down.
冷静一点 好啦 听接下来的话
Calm down-- All right, listen to this.
会让你的心情变好
It'll make you feel better.
第四条指令呢？
What about the fourth directive?
第四条指令
Fourth directive:
如果芬奇不在 机器人必须保护小狗
In Finch's absence,robot must protect the welfare of dog.
本条指令优先于所有其他指令
This directive supersedesall other directives.
听到没？
You hear that?
你明白这只狗对我有多重要吧？
So, you understandhow important this dog is to me?
是
Yes.
你知道芬奇是谁吗？
So, you know who Finch is?
你是芬奇
You are Finch.
对
Yes.
请定义“不在”
Now... define absence.
不在现场的状态
The state of not being present.
芬奇
Finch...
是
Yes?
你什么时候会不在？
When will you be absent?
该死
Oh, shit.
盖死
Oh, sheet.
你好 小狗
Hello, dog.
我知道一万六千条趣味知识 是关于…
I know 16,000 interesting facts about--
你好 芬奇
Hello, Finch.
我正将你和本地气象站连线
I'm connecting youto a local weather station.
接收到时告诉我
Tell me when you see it.
已连接
Connected.
我需要你用这些数据进行预报
I need you to use this datato make a forecast.
数据说明存在15个不同的天气事件
Data indicates 15 separate weather events
正以时速250公里接近
advancing at 155 miles per hour.
现时数据预测这些事件
Current data predictsthese events will intersect
将在未来24小时内于目前的地点汇合
over this locationwithin the next 24 hours.
会持续多久？
How long will it last?
这些事件合在一起创造超级风暴的概率为1.00452…
Probability these combined eventswill create a superstorm is 1.00452--
不…我要知道持续多久时间？
No. No, I need to knowhow long it will last.
约40天
Forty days, approximately.
所以我们必须赶快离开圣路易斯
So we need to getthe hell out of St. Louis.
南部不可能
South is out of the question.
最近暴风天气频繁 肯定不能去那
Not with the storm season we've had.
已毁灭
北部也一样
As is north, obviously.
东部有太多城市了
And east, too many cities.
你知道那意味着什么吗？
You know what that means?
太多人
People.
算了
Pass.
所以只剩一个选择了
So that's that, then.
向西进发
Head west.
旧金山
越过群山
Over the mountains.
节约粮食 节约粮食
Go easy on the rations. Go easy on the rations.
如果运气好
A little bit of luck.
找到没有被洗劫过或掠夺过的地方
Find placesthat haven't been ransacked or looted.
旧金山
San Francisco.
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
对 我觉得是时候了
Yeah, I think it's time.
你在做什么 芬奇？
What are you doing, Finch?
我在提高你的传输速度
I'm increasing your transfer rate.
我并不想这样 但我们没时间了
It's not what I want,but we're out of time.
你能说得简单一点吗？
Can you simplify?
如果不在风暴来袭前离开我们大家都会死在这里
If we don't go before that storm hits,we'll die down here. All of us.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
是 是
Yes. Yes.
所以一旦你学会行走 我们就出发
So, as soon as you can walk,we're leaving.
但是 芬奇
But, Finch...
如果我们现在离开 数据传输只达到72%
if we leave now,data transfer would only be at 72%.
毕竟不是所有人都能当爱因斯坦
Well, we can't all be Einstein.
你知道阿尔伯特爱因斯坦出生时脑袋奇大吗？
Did you know Albert Einsteinwas born with an abnormally large head?
我给你装了数码水平仪
I gave you digital levelers.
还装了冗余陀螺仪 所以你的平衡没问题
And redundant gyros, so...it's not your balance.
而是要掌握好节奏
It's your rhythm.
看着我 跟我学 原地踏步
Watch me and imitate. Walking in place.
一、二…
One, two. One, two. One, two.
一、二… 一、二…
One, two. One, two. One, two. One, two. One, two. One, two.
-很好 停  -一、二…
-Good. Good. Stop. Stop.  -One, two. One, two.
好了 这是向前走
All right. All right.Now, this is walking forward...
一、二…
One, two. One, two. One, two.
转身…然后一、二
Turning... and one, two.
一、二…
One, two. One, two.
明白吗？
Understood?
好的
Okay.
All right.
跟我学 向前
And imitate. Forward.
一、二
One, two.
行走
Walking.
对 不错
Yeah. Good.
停下
And stop.
转身
Turning.
停下
Stop.
正在停下
Stopping.
不错 很好
That's good. Good.
不 这里 嘿
No, here. Hey.
看
Look.
向我走来
Walk to me.
一、二…
One, two. One, two. One, two. One, two.
一 芬奇
One, Finch.
-一、二  -这是跌倒
-One, two.  -Now, that's falling.
一、二
One, two.
一、二、一
One, two. One.
我在行走
I am walking.
杜威？
Dewey?
杜威
Dewey.
我没事
I am okay.
抱歉
Sorry.
这是1984年款弗利特伍德南风房车
This is a 1984 Fleetwood Southwind.
紫外线辐射较强 请小心
UV radiation high. Caution.
你好 小狗
Hello, dog.
温度 摄氏64度
Temperature, 147 degrees.
关于这辆车我知道3027个趣味知识
I know 3,027 interesting factsabout this vehicle.
需要我驾驶吗？
Would you like me to drive?
不 你刚学会走路
No, you just learned how to walk.
等等…我坐下再开
Wait, wait. Let me sit down.
你知道圣路易斯的人口超过六十万吗？
Did you know the population of St. Louisis over 600,000?
人都去哪了？
Where is everybody?
说来话长
It's a long story.
我们进入山地后应该就安全了
Yeah, we should be safeonce we get into the mountains.
芬奇 我们的目的地是哪里？
Finch, what is our destination?
在我小时候 这些田地开满了野花
When I was a kid, these fieldswere covered with wildflowers.
芥菜籽、苜蓿 放眼望去五彩缤纷 芥菜籽、苜蓿 放眼望去五彩缤纷
Mustard seed, alfalfa.Color as far as the eye could see. Mustard seed, alfalfa.Color as far as the eye could see.
到了夏天还有蜜蜂
And in summertime, there were bees.
你一定会很喜欢的
You would've loved it.
芬奇 我的脑后吊着某个东西
Finch, there is somethinghanging out the back of my head.
我知道 别乱碰
I know. Don't fiddle with it.
抱歉
Sorry.
停止道歉
And stop apologizing.
抱歉
Sorry.
能安全地停车后我就帮你看看
As soon as it's safe to stop,I'll take a look.
汪汪
Woof, woof.
紫外线辐射较强 摄氏74度
UV radiation high. 165 degrees.
请小心
Caution.
-别动  -抱歉
-Hold still.  -Sorry.
这是你去过的地方的照片？
Are these all photographsof places you have been?
这是明信片
Those are postcards.
对了 乱翻别人的私人物品是很无礼的
For the record, it's rude to riflethrough a man's personal effects.
明信片
Postcards.
像信一样寄出的卡片？
Like a card sent in the post?
对…以前人们会这么做
Yes. Yes, people actually used to do that.
那是在互联网出现以前
Before this thing they call the Internet.
为什么？
Why?
这样亲朋好友就能保持联系
So friends and family could stay in touch.
那是谁寄的？
Who sent that one?
-糟糕  -怎么回事？
-Oops.  -What was that?
没什么…别乱动就好
Nothing. Nothing. Just stop fidgeting.
抱歉
Sorry.
那是谁寄给你的？
Who sent you that one?
旧金山的一位叔叔
An uncle in San Francisco.
这张呢？
And this one?
那是伦敦塔桥
Well, that's the Tower Bridge in London.
那是纽约布鲁克林大桥
And that'sthe Brooklyn Bridge in New York.
那是悉尼海港大桥
And that's Sydney Harbour Bridge.
悉尼海港？
Sydney Harbour?
我很想看看这座桥
I would like to see this bridge very much.
我们不如把那里当作目的地吧 芬奇 我们不如把那里当作目的地吧 芬奇
Maybe we shouldmake this our destination, Finch. Maybe we shouldmake this our destination, Finch.
悉尼有点远
Well, Sydney's pretty far away.
不如去近一点的地方 比如旧金山？
Why not something a little closer,like San Francisco?
那里离这多远？
How far away is that?
准确距离为2915公里
1,811 miles exactly.
也许我们可以一起去看看
Maybe we'll see it together.
好 完成
There. All done.
完好如新
Good as new.
我们得上路了
Well, we have got toget this show on the road.
你还有许多东西要学
You have a lot to learn.
不 杜威 给大家伙一个机会
No, Dewey.Let's let the big fella have a turn.
观察并模仿我
Watch me then imitate.
第一课
Now, lesson number one...
Lesson number one.
永远不放过获得下一顿饭的机会
Never pass on the opportunityfor your next meal.
尤其是当你有一只饥饿的小狗等着吃饭
Especially when you havea hungry dog to feed.
比如那边的电影院
Like that theater there.
你瞧 门上的挂锁仍是完整的
You see, the padlocks on the doorsare still intact.
仍是完整的
They are still intact.
意味着里面的东西还在 意味着里面的东西还在
That means whatever was insideis still inside. That means whatever was insideis still inside.
紫外线辐射较强
UV radiation high.
-第二课  -请小心
-And lesson number two...  -Caution.
看上面 天空有很多洞 就像瑞士芝士一样
Up there, there are holes in the sky.It's like Swiss cheese.
-看上面 就像瑞士芝士一样  -我花了一段时间才弄清情况
-Up there, it's like Swiss cheese.  -Took me awhile to figure that out.
耀斑爆发时 将臭氧层完全破坏
When the flare hit,it completely fried the ozone,
然后电磁脉冲瞬间将一切电器都损毁了
and then the EMP took outeverything electrical just like that.
幸好我当时在上班
It was a good thing I was at work.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我在定位芝士的位置
I was locating the cheese.
过来
Come here.
但是 芬奇 你说上面就像瑞士芝士一样
But, Finch,you said up there it's like Swiss cheese.
-我正在定位芝士的位置  -嘿 这不是开玩笑
-I was locating the cheese.  -Hey, this is not a joke.
我穿这套防紫外线服不是为了好玩
I don't wear this UV suit for fun.
这不是开玩笑我穿这套防紫外线服不是为了好玩
This is not a joke.I don't wear this UV suit for fun.
你为什么学我说话？
Why are you imitating me?
你说观察并模仿你
You said watch then imitate.
-停止模仿我  -抱歉
-Stop imitating me.  -Sorry.
也停止道歉
And stop apologizing.
停止中
Stopping.
第三课
Lesson number three is:
永远不要故意毁坏他人的物品
Never willfully destroysomebody else's property. Never willfully destroysomebody else's property.
斯普灵菲尔德莎士比亚节 斯普灵菲尔德莎士比亚节
多点肌肉总是好的
A little extra muscle wouldn't hurt.
帮我开门
Help me open this door.
肌肉
Muscle.
肌肉太多了
That was a little too much muscle.
你能说得简单一点吗？
Can you simplify?
这是一种比喻
That's a figure of speech.
也就是用另一种说法表达意思和芝士一样
It's another way of saying something,like the cheese.
和芝士一样
Like the cheese.
对 和芝士一样 不过不一样
Yeah, like the cheese. Except not exactly.
无事生非
芬奇 这是威廉莎士比亚的剧作
Finch, this is a playby William Shakespeare.
一部剧情喜剧 关于爱
A dramatic comedy about love,
欺骗和其他的人类误解…
deception, and other human misunders--
我从来没喜欢过戏剧
Never really cared for the theater.
第四课
Lesson number four:
发挥主观能动性
Use your initiative.
-芬奇 你觉得吃这个安全吗？  -拿着这个
-Finch, do you think this is safe to eat?-Hold this.
-大约15年了  -就是这样
-It is approximately 15 years old.  -Just like that.
你知道这为什么称为爆米花？
Now why do you thinkthey called it popcorn, huh?
第五课 享受生活
Lesson number five: Live a little.
试试吧
Go ahead.
对
Yeah.
再来
Again.
再来…
Again, again!
发现龙卷风 请寻找掩蔽地点
Tornado detection. Shelter advised.
气压…
Air pressure--
该死 我以为在到达这个海拔之前龙卷风就会消散
Damn it. I thought it would break upbefore it reached this altitude.
体温较高 摄氏39度
Body temperature high, 102.2.
气压下降
Air pressure drop.
芬奇 我的脑袋中有什么在晃动
Finch, there is something rattling aroundinside of my head.
请寻找掩蔽地点
Shelter advised.
-龙卷风警告 请寻找掩蔽地点  -别动…
-Tornado warning. Shelter advised.  -Stay. Stay, boy.
别动 乖狗狗
Stay. Good dog.
龙卷风警告 请寻找掩蔽地点
Tornado warning. Shelter advised.
跟我来
Follow me.
别动…
Stay, boy. Stay.
我们要用这些长钉和绞盘将房车固定在地面
We need to tie the RV downwith these spikes and the winches.
看见我在做什么吗？
You see what I'm doing?
你要准确地模仿我的动作 明白吗？
You need to imitate me exactly.Understand?
明白
Understand.
550米 550米
1,800 feet. 1,800 feet.
请寻找掩蔽地点
Shelter advised.
-确保缆线绷紧  -绷紧
-Make sure there is no slack on the cable.  -No slack.
520米
1,700 feet.
龙卷风警告
Tornado warning.
请寻找掩蔽地点
Shelter advised.
好的 下一个 再给我一个
All right, the next one.Give me the next one.
-龙卷风警告 430米  -我还是什么都看不见
-Tornado warning. 1,400 feet.  -I still can't see anything.
-来吧 天啊 加油  -请小心 心率较高
-Come on. Oh, my God. Come on.  -Caution. Heart rate high.
你能做到的
You can do this.
你应该回到房车上
You should returnto the recreational vehicle.
370米
1,200 feet.
270米
900 feet.
嘿
Hey.
来 很好 真不错
Here. Good. Oh, good.
请寻找掩蔽地点
Shelter advised.
150米
500 feet.
快回来
Get back in here.
快点 回到车上
Come on! Get back in!
我们必须留在车里
We gotta be inside right now!
请寻找掩蔽地点
Shelter advised.
去后面
Get in the back.
-后面…  -杜威 不是说你
-The back. The back.  -Dewey! Not you.
90米
300 feet.
芬奇 我该做什么？
Finch, what should I do?
抓紧某件东西
Hang on to something.
-60米  -谁最乖？
-200 feet.  -Who's a good boy?
抓好了 芬奇
Holding on, Finch.
15米 最后警告 请小心
50 feet. Extreme caution.
请寻找掩蔽地点
Shelter advised.
我没事
I am okay.
大家都没事吗？
Everyone okay?
你还好吗？
You good, boy?
杜威 你呢？
Dewey? You?
谢谢 我还在想那个去哪了
Thanks. I wondered what happened to that.
不太走运啊
This could have gone better.
它把肌肉用在这里了
He used his muscle on that.
嘿 你做得很好
Hey. Good job.
芬奇
Finch.
该死的
Damn it.
我们很幸运 非常幸运
We have been very fortunate.Extremely fortunate.
弗利特伍德南风房车的安全性能并不好
The Fleetwood Southwindis not known for its safety features.
-你知道吗…  -你找到千斤顶了吗？
-Did you know that---Did you find the jack?
我找到了一个备胎 但没找到千斤顶
I have located a spare but no jack.
很好 轮胎裂开了 但没有千斤顶
Great. Shredded tire, no jack.
犯错会送命 温伯格 这点你早该明白了
Mistakes will get you killed, Weinberg.You should know that by now.
芬奇
Finch.
主观能动性
Initiative.
好的
All right.
好的 放下来
Okay, let her down.
很好
Good.
我很喜欢做千斤顶
I really enjoyed being a jack.
你很擅长做千斤顶
You do make a good jack.
我们…
You know, we...
应该考虑给你起个名字了 应该考虑给你起个名字了
We should consider giving you a name. We should consider giving you a name.
我很愿意
I would like that very much.
千斤顶如何？
Well, how about Jack?
不 千斤顶是工具的名字
No, Jack is a tool's name.
威廉莎士比亚如何？你能叫我威廉莎士比亚吗？
How about William Shakespeare?Will you call me William Shakespeare?
那名字已经有人用了
That's taken.
起个没那么复杂的名字吧 简单点的
Maybe something a little less complicated.You know? Keep it simple.
拿破仑波拿巴
Napoleon Bonaparte.
拿破仑很矮
Napoleon was short.
很矮有什么问题吗？
And what is wrong with being short?
没有 但你不矮 你很高
Nothing at all. It's just thatyou are not short. You're very tall.
我非常高
I am very tall.
我喜欢罗福这个名字
I like the name Rover.
罗福是小狗的名字
Rover is a dog's name.
我说的是早期着陆火星的那部火星车
I was thinking ofthe early Mars planetary lander.
好吧 还是想一个更简单或更合适的名字吧
Okay. Still, maybe somethinga little less complicated or appropriate.
一个不是总被用作狗名的名字 一个不是总被用作狗名的名字
Maybe you want somethingthat's not already a dog's name? Maybe you want somethingthat's not already a dog's name?
不要
No.
为什么小狗没有名字？
Why doesn't the dog have a name?
它有名字
He does have a name.
它叫古德耶尔
It's Goodyear.
我喜欢这个名字
I like that name.
为什么不用这个名字叫它？毕竟它是你的狗
Why not use it? He is your dog after all.
它不是我的狗
Well, he's not my dog.
它不属于任何人
He is his own dog.
而且只有我们俩 要名字有什么用？
Besides, with just the two of us,who needs names?
杰夫
Jeff.
杰夫？
Jeff?
杰夫
Jeff.
杰夫 真的？
Jeff. Really?
我说了什么好笑的话吗？
Have I said something funny?
不 当然没有 不是
No. No, absolutely not. No.
这个名字短而简单
It is short and simple.
是的
Yes, it is.
-正如你所建议的 芬奇  -对
-Just like you suggested, Finch.  -Yeah.
而且我查过了
And I've checked.
它不是狗名
It isn't a dog's name.
没错 绞尽脑汁
No, it's not. For the life of me,
我也想不出哪只狗叫杰夫 所以…
I cannot ever remembera dog named Jeff, so...
那么 若你允许 芬奇
Then, with your permission, Finch...
不需要经过我允许
None required.
把你的手给我
Give me your hand.
另一只手 同一边的手
Other hand. Corresponding hand.
握手
And shake hands.
欢迎来到这个世界 杰夫
Welcome to the world, Jeff.
嘿…
Hey, hey, hey!
你们在闹什么？
What's going on with all the fuss?
我觉得如果我会说狗语我们的沟通会更顺畅
I thought our communication might improveif I learn to talk dog.
我进行了比较分析
I have made a comparative analysis.
我认为我已识别出若干基本音节单位
I believe I have isolatedseveral root phonetic units.
然而 它似乎误解了我所说的一切
However, it seems to have misunderstoodeverything I have said.
-它怎么了 芬奇？  -不是“它”
-What is the matter with it, Finch?-It's not an "it."
是“他”
It's a "him."
不存在狗语这种东西
There's no such thing as dog talk.
我觉得它不喜欢我
I don't think it likes me.
它还不信任你
Well, he doesn't trust you yet.
这需要时间
That takes time.
盐湖城 旧金山
旧金山
芬奇 我不太理解信任这个概念
Finch, I'm not sure I understandthis concept of trust.
你能为我解释一下吗？
Can you explain for me, please?
好的 信任是指我们…
Okay. Trust is when we...
信任是…我们 你知道 信任的时候
Well, trust is how we, you know, trust.
是…
It's...
不如我给你讲个故事吧？
Well, how about if I tell you a story?
你要给我讲关于信任的故事吗？
Are you going to tell mea story about trust?
是一个关于我的故事
Well, it's a story about me. All right.
好的 那么 很久以前
All right, so once upon a time,
我还在TAE技术公司当初级职员时 我还在TAE技术公司当初级职员时
back when I was a junior at Tri Alpha, back when I was a junior at Tri Alpha,
有来自最上级的消息说我将加入一支团队
word came from up topthat I was gonna be put on a team
那支团队正在开发RMS系统
that was developing the RMS system.
问题是我不喜欢团队工作
Problem was that I didn't reallylike working on a team,
-所以我遇到了问题…  -你为什么不喜欢
-so I was having some problems---Why didn't you like
团队工作 芬奇？
working on a team, Finch?
因为我团队的人是一群白痴
Because my teamwas a bunch of knuckleheads.
-放下…  -什么是白痴…
-Put that down. Put that down.  -What's a knuckle--
什么是白痴？
What's a knucklehead?
我只是在独自工作时效果更好 听我说
I just worked better by myself, okay?Now listen.
-正在听  -好的
-Listening.  -All right.
我们在将操作系统连接至硬件时遇到问题
Now, we were having real problemsgetting the OS to talk to the hardware.
团队很肯定问题出在硬件
And the team was certainthat it was a hardware issue.
但我知道不是的 原因在其他地方
But I knew it wasn't.It was something else.
猜猜最后谁解决了问题？
And guess who cracked it?
总之 那不重要
Well, anyway, that doesn't matter.
接下来
The next thing I know,
TAE技术公司的创始人诺曼罗斯托克博士
is Doctor Norman Rostoker,who founded TAE Technologies,
来看我们了
he pays us a visit.
那可是大事
And that is a big deal.
他表扬了我们 然后专门找到我
He pats us on the backand then he singles me out.
他说：“温伯格”
He says, "Weinberg."
他知道我的名字
The man knows my name.
没错 他说
That's right. He said,
“温伯格 我听说解决方案是你一人想出来的 是吗？”
"Weinberg, I heard you figured this outall by yourself. Is that true?"
我得仔细思考怎么回答
And I had to think about thatfor a minute.
但是 我知道我必须说什么
But then I knew what I had to say.
所以我告诉他 如果没有我的团队我是不会想出来的
And so I told himI couldn't have done it without my team.
但你说你的团队是一群白痴
But you said your team werea bunch of knuckleheads.
他直视着我的眼睛 他知道我在说谎
Well, he looked me right in the eye,and he knew I was lying.
但他也知道我不会背叛团队
But he also knew I had my team's back.
所以他对我眨了眨眼 然后告诉我们
So he gave me this wink and told us all,
“团队工作 那才是关键”
"Teamwork. That's the key."
团队工作是关键
Teamwork is the key.
-对  -眨眨眼
-Yeah.  -Wink, wink.
对
That's right.
我不确定这个故事的涵义是什么 芬奇
I'm not sure I understandwhat the story was about, Finch.
-思考一下  -我在思考
-Well, think about it.  -I am.
它的涵义是建立信任 让他人信任你
It's about building trustand getting other people to trust you.
是的 但是你并不信任你的团队 芬奇
Yes, but you didn't actuallytrust your team, Finch.
我觉得这个故事很难理解
And I found the storyquite hard to follow.
我能否建议…
May I suggest--
芬奇
Finch.
芬奇 需要我驾驶吗？
Finch, would you like me to drive?
-探测到紫外线辐射 摄氏61度  -我只需要几分钟 -探测到紫外线辐射 摄氏61度-我只需要几分钟
-UV radiation detected, 141 degrees.  -I just need a few minutes. -UV radiation detected, 141 degrees.  -I just need a few minutes.
你们俩…
I want you two...
开始努力
to start working on...
建立信任吧
that trust.
-好吗？  -像故事里说的一样？
-Okay?-Like in the story?
对 和故事里说的一样
Yeah, yeah. Just like in the story.
留在遮阴处
Stay in the shade.
别这样
Come on.
来吧
-嘿 不  -来吧
-Hey, no.  -Come on.
不…不是那样
No. No, no, not that way.
-来吧  -别这样
-Come on.  -Come on.
过来 好的
Come here. Okay, okay.
把绳子给我 我来吧
Give me this. Give me this.
嘿 乖孩子 来吧
Hey, come on, boy. Come on.
就这样 对
There you go. Yeah.
我说过它不喜欢我吧
I told you he doesn't like me.
你留在这里
You just stay here.
守卫堡垒
Guard the fort.
我们吃点什么呢？
What should we have?
爪子不能上桌
Get your elbows off the table.
爪子不能上桌 拿下去
Get your elbows off the table.Off the table. Down.
放飞心灵
芝士通心粉
Mac and cheese.
我要点一份三层火鸡三文治
I'm gonna get a triple-decker turkey club.
该死
Shit.
别动
Stay.
嘿
Hey!
不 嘿…来 嘿 不 嘿…来 嘿
No! Hey, hey, come. Hey. No! Hey, hey, come. Hey.
过来这边 很好
Come here. Good, good, good.
别动
Stay.
嘿 怎么回事 杰夫？
Hey, what's going on, Jeff?
没什么？
Nothing.
你刚才是开房车了吗？
Did you just drive the RV?
没有
No.
没有？
No?
但它确实动了
It did roll though.
好吧
Oh, okay. Good.
因为我觉得你还没准备好开房车
Because I don't think you're quite readyto drive the RV yet.
我观察过你开车
I have seen you drive.
你不开心吗？
Are you upset?
你仔细听我说
I need you to listen to me, okay?
好的
Okay.
找到防紫外线服 拿给我
I want you to fetch the UV suitand bring it to me.
头盔、冷却箱 还有其他的
The helmet, the cooling unit,everything, okay?
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
明白吗？
Is that understood?
明白
Understood.
不…
No, no! No!
不
No!
不…
No, no!
不
No!
我的意思是走过来
I meant on foot!
不 停下
No, stop! Stop!
我是出色的司机
I am an excellent driver.
过来
Come here.
紫外线对所有人一视同仁狗皮肤、人类皮肤 都会烧毁
UV doesn't discriminate.Dog skin, human skin, they both fry.
-我以为你希望我…  -我只交代了你一件事
-I thought you wanted me---You have one job to do.
照顾好这只狗 这是我制造你的原因
Take care of this dog.It's the reason I made you.
这是你存在的唯一原因
It's the only reason you exist.
第四条指令
The fourth directive.
我不需要同伴 我不需要朋友
I don't need companionship.I don't need a friend.
我需要你做好你的本职
I need you to do your job.
对不起 我…
I'm sorry. I am--
我知道你昨天才来到这个世界上但你该长大了
I know you were born yesterday,but it's time for you to grow up!
说实话 打从一开始你就是一场疯狂的赌博
God's honest truth, you werea crazy gamble from start to finish.
你必须明白我们多么脆弱
You just need to understandhow vulnerable we are.
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
现在也是时候了
Now is as good a time as any.
是时候做什么？
What for?
慢慢…
Now gently. Very gently.
加一点油门
Give it just a little gas.
别急
Don't rush it.
轻一点
Just very gently.
这不叫轻
That's not gently.
-抱歉  -你知道轻的意思
-Sorry.  -You know what gently means.
小心
Easy.
小心…
Easy now. Easy.
小心
Easy.
别把方向盘打过了
Don't oversteer.
对 你打得太过了 这叫转向过度
Yeah, you've oversteered.That's oversteering.
-抱歉  -把脚稍微抬起一点点
-Sorry.  -Ease your foot up just a hair.
不错
Good.
好的 保持平稳 就像现在这样
All right. Now keep it steady,just like this.
很好
Perfect.
我知道 看路
I know-- Eyes on the road.
这辆车很费油 但我做了一些改造
Now, she's a little thirsty,but I made some modifications.
如果保持平稳速度行驶在时速80公里以下 那就没问题
So if we can keep it steady,under 50, we should be okay.
很好
Good. Yeah.
我是出色的司机
I am an excellent driver.
先别翘尾巴
Well, don't get ahead of yourself.
眼睛看路
Eyes on the road.
你瞧吧 雨人 你不过是学徒
See, rain man? You're just an apprentice.
那我就是出色的学徒
Then I am an excellent apprentice.
好吧
Uh huh.
旧金山 我们来了
San Francisco, here we come!
今晚真冷 好久没这样了
What a cold night. It's been a long time.
芬奇
Finch.
是极光
It's the aurora borealis.
是吗？
Yeah?
如今不用去阿拉斯加也能看见了
Only now you don't have to bein Alaska to see it.
这点可以感谢耀斑
You can thank the flare for that.
再见了 臭氧层
Goodbye, ozone.
再见了 阳光洒在脸上的感觉
Goodbye, feeling the sun on your face.
植被、庄稼和粮食 一切都永别了
Vegetation and crops and food.Goodbye, everything.
然而 我们还在 然而 我们还在
And yet, here we are. And yet, here we are.
是的
Yes.
我们还在 芬奇
Here we are, Finch.
能问你一件事吗？
May I ask you something?
如果日光这么危险我们为什么不在夜间行驶？
If daylight is so dangerous,why are we not traveling at night?
如果在夜间出行是安全的你不觉得我早该知道吗？
You think if traveling at night were safe,I wouldn't know that by now?
我们的目的地是哪里？
Where are we headed?
金门大桥
The Golden Gate Bridge.
未知之地
Into the unknown.
灰尘、烟雾、摄氏70度的高温和紫外线辐射 这些我能克服
Dust and smoke and 150-degree heatand UV radiation, that I can handle.
为什么？
Why?
因为它们是可以预测的
Because it's predictable.
在夜间出行意味着不可预测的风险
Moving at night presentsthat which is not predictable.
意味着要防人
People.
躲在阴影里饥肠辘辘的人 心怀不轨的人
Starving people hiding in the shadows.People who mean you harm.
不能信任的人
People you cannot trust.
可是 为什么？你怎么知道不能信任那些人？
But why? How do you knowyou can't trust those people?
因为信任会害你送命
Because trust will get you killed.
不要信任任何人
Trust no one.
你又生我的气了
You're mad at me again.
听着 你会遇到各种事
Look, things will happen to you.
你无法控制的事
Things that you cannot control.
你会有原始的情绪
Raw emotion will find you.
在这种时候 你如何应对、采取何种行动 在这种时候 你如何应对、采取何种行动
When it does, how you deal with it,what you do... When it does, how you deal with it,what you do...
将定义你是谁
will define who you are.
你遇到这些情况了吗？
Did that happen to you?
每个人都会遇到
It happens to all of us.
无论我们是否希望如此
Whether we want it to or not.
太冷了
It's too cold.
我这把老骨头承受不了这个低温
Too cold for these old bones.
芬奇 如果可以 我想留在外面一会儿
Finch, I think I might stay here awhileif that's okay with you.
好的
Okay.
你身体有恙
You're unwell.
我没事
I'm fine.
我有什么可以做的吗？
What would you like me to do?
打电话找医生
Call a doctor.
救命
乖 别动
Good boy. Stay.
走吧 杜威
Come on, Dewey.
让我们上路吧
Let's get this show on the road.
第一课 第一课
Lesson number one: Lesson number one:
永远不放过获得下一顿饭的机会
Never pass on the opportunityfor your next meal.
第二课
Lesson number two...
丹佛医院
永远不要故意毁坏他人的物品
Never willfully destroyanother person's property.
但是多点肌肉总是好的
But a little extra muscle wouldn't hurt.
顺便一提 这是一种比喻
That's a figure of speech, by the way.
来吧 杜威
Come, Dewey.
第三课
Lesson number three:
上面就像瑞士芝士一样
Up there, it's like Swiss cheese.
紫外线辐射较强 摄氏62度
UV radiation high, 144 degrees.
请小心
Caution.
嘿
Hey.
留在这里
Stay here.
守卫堡垒
Guard the fort.
糟了
Oh, no.
第四课：发挥主观能动性
Lesson number four: Use your initiative.
药品
Medicine.
主观能动性 主观能动性
Initiative. Initiative.
第五课：享受生活
Lesson number five: Live a little.
不赖
Not bad.
别动
Stay, boy.
主观能动性…
Initiative, initiative,initiative, initiative!
不好
Oh, no.
对不起 杜威
I'm sorry, Dewey.
来吧
Come on.
芬奇
Finch.
你喜欢我的新外套吗？
Do you like my new coat?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你到底有没有听进去我的话？ 你到底有没有听进去我的话？
Have you listened to me at all? Have you listened to me at all?
但是 主观能动性 芬奇
But-- But initiative, Finch.
主观能动性需要常识
Initiative requires common sense.
如果你有常识 就会知道这个地方不太对劲
If you had any, you'd knowthere's something wrong with this place.
芬奇 你觉得…
Finch, do you think--
快离开
Walk away now.
芬奇
Finch.
杜威在哪里？
Where's Dewey?
杜威不在了
Dewey's gone.
心率较高 每分钟150次
Heart rate high, 150 bpm.
门 快关门
The door. Get the door.
请小心
Caution.
心率较高
Heart rate high.
拿好这个
Here, take this.
-请小心  -来控制方向盘
-Caution.  -Now come take the wheel.
体温较高 摄氏40度
Body temperature high, 104.8.
血压较高
Blood pressure high.
-我能否建议…  -不能
-May I make a suggestion---No!
你不能 那是个陷阱 而你直直走进去
No, you may not. That was a trapand you walked right into it.
杜威是我们的一员现在它离开了 都因为你愚蠢的错误
Dewey was one of us and now he's goneall because of your stupid mistake.
-请小心 心率较高  -来吧
-Caution. Heart rate high.  -Come on, boy.
来 过来 宝贝来 去吧…
Come on. Here, boy. Come on, boy. Go. Go.
从现在开始有新的规矩
From now on, there's a new set of rules.
不能再犯错 我们犯不起更多错误了
No more mistakes.We can't afford that anymore.
你希望我做什么？
What would you like me to do?
开车 越远越好
Drive. We need the miles.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
有人在跟踪我们
We're being followed.
是吗？
We are?
是谁？
By who?
我不想知道答案
I don't want to find out.
你还是能看见路的 对吗？
You can still see, right?
我能
I can see.
我们必须甩掉他
We-- We have to lose him.
油门踩到底…踩油门
Floor it. Floor it.Put your foot on the gas.
-但是弗利特伍德手册写…  -照做就好 快点 现在就踩
-But the Fleetwood manual says---Do it. Just do it. Do it now!
快点 加快速度
Go. Go! Go faster.
我能提一个建议吗 芬奇？
May I make a suggestion, Finch?
-我们必须离开这条路  -你在做什么？
-We have to get off this road.  -What are you doing?
-天桥 那就意味着有隧道  -我不懂
-Overpass. That means an underpass.  -I don't understand.
就是现在 向左转
Now. Now! Hard left!
快点 你为什么停下？
Go. Go! Why are you stopping?
我们必须藏起来 快
We have to hide! Go!
现在就得动了
We have to go now!
-芬奇 我觉得…  -马上 快
-Finch, I think---Now! Go!
芬奇
Finch.
这个隧道的最大高度是
Maximum height ofthis particular underpass
4米
is 13 feet and 7 inches.
根据这辆车的基本定制规格 我们…
With the basic customizationsof the vehicle, we're--
芬奇
Finch!
4米
-芬奇  -我做了什么？
-Finch?-What have I done?
不 杰夫
No! No, Jeff!
我觉得他们已经走了 芬奇
I think they're gone, Finch.
我们不可能活下来
We're not gonna make it.
已经结束了
It's over.
我太老了 我病得太重了我太累了 我已经走投无路了
I'm too old. I'm too sick.I'm too tired. I'm done.
芬奇 要下雨了 你知道那意味着…
Finch, it's gonna rain.You know what that means--
别说了…接受现实吧
Stop it. Stop it. Just accept it.
已经结束了
It's over.
不
No.
我们不能放弃
We can't give up.
我不允许你放弃
I will not allow you to give up.
你不允许？
You will not allow it?
这轮不到你决定 因为你只是一部机器
Well, you don't get to decidebecause you're just a machine.
机器人不能伤害人类
A robot cannot harm a human or,through inaction,
也不能坐视人类受到伤害
allow a human to come to harm.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我能问你一个问题吗？
May I ask you something?
你觉得我们能到达金门大桥吗？
Do you think we'll make itto the Golden Gate Bridge?
我认为我们能
I think we will.
你想知道原因吗？
You wanna know why?
因为我相信你 芬奇
Because I believe in you, Finch.
我能给你讲个故事吗？
Can I tell you a story?
好的
Okay.
很久以前
Once upon a time...
爆发了太阳耀斑
there was a solar flare.
但耀斑没有让人类灭亡这一切都是我们自己造成的
But the flare didn't finish us off.We did that to ourselves.
有的人闭门不出
Some people hid and locked their doors.
假装什么都没发生
Tried to pretendthat it wasn't really happening.
那些人没有撑多久就死了
And they didn't last very long.
我们其余人尽己所能存活下去
The rest of us did what we had to doto survive.
我们四处搜刮物品 争抢剩下的东西
We scavenged and we fought overwhatever was left behind
直到一切都抢光
until there was nothing left.
我在搜一家超市
I was searching this supermarket.
东西几乎已经被人拿光了
And the place had beenpretty well cleaned out,
但走运的话 偶尔能找到被人漏掉的东西
but occasionally something gets overlookedand you get lucky.
我发现了一袋面条 我发现了一袋面条
And I found a bag of noodles. And I found a bag of noodles.
古德耶尔轮胎促销
但在我离开前
But before I could leave...
有个母亲带着孩子来了
this mother and her kid show up,
她们推着一台购物车 装满了她们的东西
and they have a shopping cartfilled with their things.
小女孩估计九岁都不到
The little girl couldn't have beenmore than nine years old.
她背着一个粉色的独角兽图案背包
She had a pink unicorn backpack.
她的手里握着枪
And she was holding a gun in her hands.
我听见那个妈妈说：“记住 看到任何人
And I heard the mom say,"Remember, if you see anyone,
用枪指着他们像我展示给你看的那样做 好吗？”
you point at themand you do like I showed you, okay?"
然后我意识到 如果她看到我
And then I realized that if she sees me,
小女孩会开枪射死我 拿走我的面条
this little girl's gonna shoot meand take my noodles.
于是我藏起来了
So I hid.
等她们走了再出来
And waited until they were done.
但她们正要离开时有一辆旅行车驶来 停在外面
But as they were leaving,this station wagon pulled up.
司机下车了 因为他看见了小女孩
And the driver got outbecause he'd seen the little girl.
他在大叫
And he was yelling,
他挥舞着一把霰弹枪 像疯子一样
and he was waving a shotgun aroundlike a crazy man.
他看到购物车 想把东西据为己有
He'd seen the cartand he wanted what was in it.
所以他大嚷：“交给我…”
So he was hollering,"Hand it over. Hand it over."
然后那个妈妈跑过去 对他大喊
And then the mom ran upand she was yelling at him,
“离我们远点”
"Leave us alone."
小女孩很怕
And the little girl is terrified and...
她不知道该用枪指着哪里
she didn't know where to point the gun.
她在哭
She was crying.
她们都在尖叫
And they were both screaming.
然后 砰砰几声
And then bang, bang, bang.
一切都发生得那么快
It all happened so fast.
等他离开后 我终于能来到她们身边
By the time he leftand I was able to get to them,
太迟了
it was too late.
然后我听见一个声音
Then I heard this sound.
微弱的哼哼声
This tiny whimpering...
从小女孩的粉色背包里传出来
coming from the girl's pink backpack.
于是我打开背包
And so I opened it.
里面是一只颤抖的小家伙 里面是一只颤抖的小家伙
And there was this shivering,tiny, little thing. And there was this shivering,tiny, little thing.
那么害怕
So frightened.
那么孤单
And so alone.
饥饿让人变成杀人犯
Hunger turned men into murderers.
但是…
But made...
让我变成懦夫
made me a coward.
你怎么能相信这样的人？
How can you believe in that?
旧金山
看到了吗？
You see that?
旧金山
San Francisco.
芬奇
Finch.
只有770公里了
Only 480 miles.
亲爱的芬奇 我明年将路过旧金山我们能见个面吗？ 爸爸
“爸爸”
"Dad."
爸爸
Dad.
紫外线辐射较低 非危险水平
UV radiation low. Non-critical.
你应该来看看
I think you need to come and see this.
-芬奇  -什么？
-Finch!-What?
-什么？  -那里
-What?-Right there.
我不是故意撞到它的
I didn't mean to hit it.
你不是说…
I thought you said it...
瑞士芝士
Swiss cheese.
我不知道
I don't know.
这太棒了 杰夫
This is excellent, Jeff.
这是我很久以来所吃过最好的一顿饭了
This is the best meal I've hadin a long, long time.
你知道吗？
Guess what?
什么？
What?
我昨晚在脑中看见了那个画面
I saw it in my head last night.
在脑中？
In your head?
我们三个在金门大桥上
The three of us were onthe Golden Gate Bridge,
就像还没发生的一幅画
like a painting that hasn't been yet.
哇
Wow!
杰夫 你做梦了？
Jeff, you had a dream?
我好震惊
That blows my mind.
我真想看到五、六年后的你
I would love to see youfive or six years from now.
我没有让人失望？ 我没有让人失望？
I'm not a disappointment? I'm not a disappointment?
当然没有
Of course not. No.
我不应该说你是机器
And I shouldn't have called you a machine.
我能问你一件事吗？
May I ask you something?
你说金门大桥的明信片是你叔叔寄的
You said that the Golden Gate Bridge cardwas from your uncle,
但是它的背面落款是“爸爸”
but on the back it's signed "Dad."
为什么？
Why is that?
老天 你不会错过一个细节 对吗？
Boy, you don't miss a thing, do you?
对 我不会
No, I don't.
好的 故事时间到
Well, I think it's time for another story.
这个…
Well...
我妈妈总说我爸爸的体内流着维京人的血
My mom always said my dadhad Viking blood in him.
你没说“很久以前”
You didn't say, "Once upon a time."
好的 很久以前
Okay. And once upon a time...
他离开了我们
he left us.
那是在我出生之前的事 那是在我出生之前的事
It was before I was born. It was before I was born.
他参军了
He was in the army.
据说他是什么工程师 建造大桥的
An engineer of some kind, evidently.Built bridges.
他总是四处旅行 我们从未联络过
And he was always traveling.We never had any contact.
然后 在我15岁生日那天突然收到这张明信片
And then on my 15th birthday,that postcard shows up out of the blue.
金门大桥的那张
The one with the Golden Gate Bridge.
他在上面写道希望有天能和我见面
And he wrote on ithe hoped we could meet one day.
在那个时候 我应该出发去看世界了
Meantime I was supposed togo off and see the world.
他的落款是“爸爸”我把这张明信片视若珍宝
And he signed it "Dad" and I treasured it.
其实 我年龄一到立即就去买了这身高档西服
In fact, as soon as I was old enough,I went out and I bought this fancy suit.
心想我们终于相见的那天
And I thought, well,when we finally do meet,
我要给他留个好印象 让他为我自豪
I wanted to impress himand make him feel proud of me.
那之后再也没有他的消息了
Never heard from him again.
那你做到了吗？
And did you?
做到什么？
Did I what?
你去看世界了吗？ 你去看世界了吗？
Did you go see the world? Did you go see the world?
我曾去过一次纽约
Well, I went to New York City once.
-是吗？  -我不太喜欢那里
-Yeah?-I didn't much care for it.
人多又脏
It was crowded and dirty.
此外 我没怎么离开过密苏里
And apart from that I've never beenmuch further than Missouri.
总是有各种各样的阻碍
But there was always something.
我的健康、工作、妈妈、世界末日等等
You know, my health or my work,Mom, the end of the world.
对 我…
Yeah, I...
我一直没找到机会
I just never got around to it.
其他明信片呢？为什么都是空白的？
What about the other postcards?Why are they all blank?
我看到喜欢的明信片就会买下
Well, whenever I saw one I liked,I would buy it.
像是收藏吧 某种人生愿望清单
You know, sort of a collection.Something for the bucket list, I guess.
我也说不清
I don't know.
我们人类就是充满各种矛盾
Like, we humansare full of contradictions.
你已经可以跟我说出 你已经可以跟我说出
You see, you can already tell me You see, you can already tell me
金门大桥上有多少颗铆钉
how many rivetsare in the Golden Gate Bridge.
用了多长的悬索 桥有多高
And how many miles of cable were usedand how high it is.
但是只有当你站在上面 看到它的美
But it's not until you actuallystand on it and see the beauty,
听到悬索在风中歌唱…
and listen to the suspension cablessinging in the wind...
这是一种体验
That's experience.
是一种人类的体验
That's human experience.
不只是想象 而是生活
It's not just imagining, it's living.
但你还没去过金门大桥 芬奇
But you've never actually beento the Golden Gate Bridge, Finch.
是的 杰夫 我没去过
No, Jeff, I've never been.
谢谢
Thank you.
正如我说的 人类充满矛盾
Like I said,humans are full of contradictions.
我真希望我更好地利用了我过去的时间
I wish I'd done more with the time I had.
那我们现在就出发吧 芬奇
Well, then let's leave right now, Finch!
我们现在就出发
We'll leave right now.
如果现在出发 只需要18小时33分钟… 如果现在出发 只需要18小时33分钟…
And if we leave right now,it'll only be 18 hours, 33 minutes-- And if we leave right now,it'll only be 18 hours, 33 minutes--
我快死了 杰夫
I'm dying, Jeff.
我会死去
I'm gonna die.
当我离开时
When I'm gone...
你保证会为古德耶尔做正确的事吗？
do you promiseto do what's right for Goodyear?
你的球呢？
Where's your ball?
在这里吗？是你的球吗？
Is it here? Is that your ball?
那是你的球吗？
Is that your ball?
你的球呢？
Where's your ball? Where's your ball?
去吧 快追
Go! Get it.
来吧 好的
Come on. All right. Okay.
你来试试
Now you try it.
对 你来扔
Yeah. Yeah. You throw it.
来吧 扔吧
Go ahead. Throw it.
这类活动很重要的
This kind of stuff's important.
你的球呢？
Where's your ball?
你的球呢？在这吗？
Where's your ball? Is it here? Is it here?
扔吧
Just throw it.
这是你的球吗？
Is this your ball?
-扔球  -给
-Throw the ball.  -Here, boy.
你的球呢？
Where's your ball?
扔球
Throw the ball.
来吧
Come on!
嘿 芬奇
Hey, Finch!
是
Yeah.
来
Here, boy!
来吧 不 来吧 不
Come on, boy. No. Come on, boy. No.
-再来一次  -但它还是把球还给你
-Again.  -But he returned it to you.
因为狗狗是习惯的动物
Well, that's 'cause dogsare creatures of habit.
给
Here, boy!
来吧
Come on.
求求你？
Please?
给他吧
Do it.
真乖…
Good boy. Good--
我说它不喜欢我吧 我说它不喜欢我吧
I told you he doesn't like me. I told you he doesn't like me.
你们俩能搞好关系的
You two will-- You'll figure it out.
来 相信我
Come on. Trust me.
我把我的高档西服弄脏了
Look what I did to ruin my fancy suit.
我扶着你
I got you.
没事的
It's okay.
试着呼吸 芬奇 保持呼吸
Try and breathe, Finch. Try and breathe.
我去躺一会儿 你们俩玩吧
I'm just gonna lay down for a while.You two play.
你们俩继续玩
You two go.
-去玩  -有什么我能做的吗 芬奇？
-Go play.  -Can I do something, Finch?
杰夫 你已经做了很多了
Jeff, you already have.
我们握握手吧
Shake my hand.
不
No.
我该怎么办？
What am I gonna do?
你该怎么做 杰夫？
What are you gonna do, Jeff?
芬奇会怎么做？
What would Finch do?
他会喂小狗吃东西
He'd feed the dog.
我要喂小狗吃东西
I'm gonna feed the dog.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
芬奇温伯格
古德耶尔和杰夫最爱的人
你已经可以跟我说出
You see, you can already tell me
金门大桥上有多少颗铆钉
how many rivets arein the Golden Gate Bridge.
用了多长的悬索 桥有多高
And how many miles of cable were usedand how high it is.
已出发去圣罗莎
但是只有当你站在上面 看到它的美
But it's not until you actuallystand on it and see the beauty,
听到悬索在风中歌唱 你才能…
and listen to the suspension cablessinging in the wind...
这是一种体验
That's experience.
索菲姨妈 我们没事来马林县找我们吧
是一种人类的体验
That's human experience.
詹妮弗李
看来不只我们来过这里
Looks like we're not the only oneswho came this way.
你觉得还有别人吗？
You think they're still out there?
只有一个办法知道答案
Well, there's only one way to find out.
真美
It's beautiful.
芬奇说得太对了
Finch knew what he was talking about.
嘿 要不要听故事？
Hey, how about a story?
好的 很久以前…
Okay, so once upon a time...
字幕翻译：易晗
请点击www.osdb.link/988y9评价此字幕帮助其他人选择最佳字幕